// Array containing questions, answers and correct answers export/import: https://javascript.info/import-export
export const quizData = [{
    question: 'Who is the steward of Gondor before Aragorn returns to claim the throne?',
    answers: ['Denethor', 'Theoden', 'Boromir', 'Sauron'],
    correctAnswer: 0
},
{
    question: 'Who is the steward of the Ring who succumbs to its power and attempts to take it for himself?',
    answers: ['Boromir', 'Faramir', 'Gimli', 'Frodo'],
    correctAnswer: 0
},
{
    question: `What is the name of the Shire's capital, where the hobbits reside?`,
    answers: ['Longbottom', 'Hardbottle', 'Bree', 'Hobbiton'],
    correctAnswer: 3
},
{
    question: "What is the name of the horse given to Aragorn by Rohan's king?",
    answers: ['Shadowfax', 'Brego', 'Hasufel', 'Asfaloth'],
    correctAnswer: 1
},
{
    question: 'Who was the founder of Rohan?',
    answers: ['Theoden', 'King Eorl', 'Halbrand', 'Aragorn'],
    correctAnswer: 1
},
{
    question: 'Who is the wizard known as the Grey Pilgrim?',
    answers: ['Gandalf', 'Radagast', 'Saruman', 'Alatar'],
    correctAnswer: 0
},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the mountain where the One Ring is destroyed?',
    answers: ['Erebor', 'Mount Doom', 'Mount Gundabad', 'Thangorodrim'],
    correctAnswer: 1
},
{
    question: 'Which character famously says, "Not all those who wander are lost"?',
    answers: ['Gandalf', 'Legolas', 'Aragorn', 'Sam'],
    correctAnswer: 2
},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the ancient language spoken by the elves in Middle-earth?',
    answers: ['Quenya', 'Eltharin', 'Ellylon', 'Sindarin'],
    correctAnswer: 3
},
{
    question: 'What is the language of Mordor, spoken by Sauron and his servants?',
    answers: ['Black Speech', 'Black Tongue', 'Dark Speech', 'Dark Tongue'],
    correctAnswer: 0
},
{
    question: 'What is the elvish city that serves as a refuge for the Fellowship in "The Fellowship of the Ring"?',
    answers: ['The Woodland Realm', 'Rivendell', 'Gondolin', 'Grey Havens'],
    correctAnswer: 1
},
{
    question: `What is Legolas's surname?`,
    answers: ['Netyoive', 'Greenleaf', 'Floshem', 'Mirkwood'],
    correctAnswer: 1

},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the river that flows through Gondor and is guarded by the fortress of Osgiliath?',
    answers: ['Bruinen', 'Glanduin', 'Carnen', 'Anduin'],
    correctAnswer: 3
},
{
    question: 'Who is the leader of the Nazgûl?',
    answers: ['Sauron', 'Saruman', 'The Mouth Of Sauron', 'The Witch-King of Angmar'],
    correctAnswer: 3
},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the fortress city ruled by the steward Denethor in Gondor?',
    answers: ['Osgiliath', 'Minas Tirith', 'Minas Morgul', 'Umbar'],
    correctAnswer: 1
},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the elf who forges the rings of power in Eregion?',
    answers: ['Celebrimbor', 'Annatar', 'Elrond', 'Arondir'],
    correctAnswer: 0

},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the horse ridden by Gandalf?',
    answers: ['Asfaloth', 'Arod', 'Shadowfax', 'Snowmane'],
    correctAnswer: 2
},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the evil spider-like creature that captures Frodo?',
    answers: ['Ungoliant', 'Shelob', 'Attercop', 'Cingwin'],
    correctAnswer: 1
},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the fortress that serves as the dwelling place of Sauron in Mordor?',
    answers: ['Minas Morgul', 'Mordor', 'Isengard', 'Barad-dûr'],
    correctAnswer: 3
},
{
    question: 'What is the name of the kingdom of the dwarves that Thorin Oakenshield seeks to reclaim in "The Hobbit"?',
    answers: ['Erebor', 'Gondor', 'The Shire', 'Rhûn', ],
    correctAnswer: 0

}
];




